Department of Spanish and Portuguese Records, ca. 1910-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Department of Spanish and Portuguese Records
ca. 1910-[ongoing]
Smith College. Dept. of Spanish and Portuguese.
RG 52
1 box (5 linear inches)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection is in one box and contains black and white photographs, news releases, newspaper articles, mid-year and final exam questions, students' class notes, and programs from theatrical performances.
Historical Note
The Spanish Department at Smith College was established in 1902. By the 1914-1915 academic year, it was named the Spanish Language and Literature Department. By 1944-1945, its name changed to the Spanish and Portuguese Languages and Literature Department. The department was later called the Hispanic Studies Department from 1966-1967 until the 1981-1982 academic year when it received its current title as the Spanish and Portuguese Department.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Department of Spanish and Portuguese records contain materials describing the department's courses, clubs, and dramatic performances. Types of materials include black and white photographs, news releases, newspaper articles, mid-year and final exam questions, students' class notes, and programs from theatrical performances.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Department of Spanish and Portuguese records were created by the department and donated to the College Archives.
Additional Information
Related Material
Researchers should also view: 42. Faculty
- Spanish Dept.-General 1930s-40s, 1954, 1963, 1991, 1995 (Box 1268, Folder 1)
- Clubs 1959, 1990, 1993 (Box 1268, Folder 2)
- Hispanic courses-100-120 1974-78 (Box 1268, Folder 3)
- Hispanic courses-200-371 1975-78 (Box 1268, Folder 4)
- Dramatics-La Molinera De Arcos 1958 (Box 1268, Folder 5)
- Dramatics-La Zapatera Prodigiosa 1955 (Box 1268, Folder 6)
- Dramatics-Romance de la Condesita 1940 (Box 1268, Folder 7)
- Dramatics-Three Cornered Hat 1958 (Box 1268, Folder 8)
- Spanish 1-lecture notes Early 1900s (Box 1268, Folder 9)
- Student's class notes on Cervantes Undated (Box 1268, Folder 10)
- Photographs 1946, 1953-54, 1980s (Box 1268, Folder 11)